# Davin Stirling

I'm an experienced IT Professional pivoting into software development, having completed courses in Java and Full Stack Web Development, and gained my Scrum Master certificate. My tech career spans over 12 years across New Zealand and the UK, ranging from service desk & application support, to systems analysis & design, plus some programming & scripting. I have a particular interest in backend technologies, and am keen to build on my experience in a collaborative and supportive environment that welcomes diversity.

https://davin2020.github.io

https://github.com/davin2020

davin.stirling+jobs@gmail.com

Near Bath, UK Entitled to work in UK & NZ

#### **CAREER HIGHLIGHTS**

#### WSP Opus 2018, support role

Key member of contractor team, successfully migrated nearly 2000 users and computers across 23 regional offices within 6 weeks

# • DDSIT 2017, support role

Taught myself PowerShell and created scripts to make repetitive & time consuming tasks more efficient

#### Kaseya 2011, headhunted for support role

Prepared and coordinated with other teams across 3 time zones, to onboard & remotely train 6 new interns, at short notice and with minimal supervision

#### Visionstream 2010, support role

Asking questions led to me gathering user requirements, and designing & documenting the front-end functionality for a new resource management website, tailored to the local market

# • Gen-i 2009, support role

Recognized by client executives "for outstanding customer support and service delivery to the account"

#### • IBM 2003, developer

Received an internal award for creating an innovative and reusable registration website in Java

#### **EXPERIENCE** (CONTRACTING)

#### **Junior Software Engineer**

CapGemini, UK (Permanent) // Sept 2022 - now

Joined project (10 months) to upgrade web, DB & SVN servers -

- Created Python Flask website to display read-only data from SQL database
- Upgraded and configured Apache Windows web server to deploy Flask app using mod\_wsgi, and legacy wiki to production
- Upgraded SVN scripts from Python 2 to 3
- Created content for client report about project deliverables
- Enhanced new network diagram after server upgrades

#### Alumni Trainee in Java Development

mthree, UK (Fixed Term) // Feb - Mar 2022

Completed intensive 6 week course about modern Java dev using Spring

Travelling in Asia and Covid Lockdown in UK // Dec 2019 - Dec 2020

Travels cut short by lockdown in March; started studying web development online in advance of 4 month bootcamp starting Sept 2020

#### **SKILLS**

Apache 2.4, mod wsgi

Python 3, Flask

PHP7 including Slim4, PHPUnit

Laravel 8

JavaScript ES6

Node.js, Express, React, Vue

MongoDB Compass & Atlas

Firebase Firestore NoSQL DB

MySQL

GraphQL API

**REST API & JSON** 

HTML5 & CSS3

Java v11 using Eclipse, Maven

Spring (JDBC, Test) & Spring Boot (JPA, Web, Thymelead, Hibernate)

OOP, SOLID & MVC design

Git & GitHub; SVN

Scrum/Agile

#### **EDUCATION**

Java Course - mthree, 2022

Full Stack Web Development Course – iO Academy, 2020

Certified Scrum Master – Agilify, 2020

First Class BSc (Hons) in Computer Science, with IBM UK – University of Portsmouth, 2003

#### **Support Consultant**

Fusion 5, NZ (Permanent) // Sep - Nov 2019

Provided internal Ivanti ITSM application support and deployed minor changes into test & live environments.

# Field Services Engineer

WSP Opus // Nov 2018 - Sep 2019

Travelled to regional offices, collaborated with IT teams and contractors to perform pre & post migration checks. Provided onsite and remote end user support to resolve issues and reduce backlog of 5,500 incidents following domain migration of mailboxes, users and assets

#### Service Desk Analyst

Provide onsite and remote end user support for various companies across different industries

Plant and Food Research // Jul - Nov 2018 Watercare // Mar - Apr 2018 DDSIT // Mar 2013 - Jul 2017

Web Developer Whyte Communications // Nov 2012 - Jan 2013

Technical Database Documentation Visionstream // Nov 2011 - Jun 2012

Analysed and wrote technical documentation, primarily the future API mapping between 2 databases. Generated formal documentation for existing system and business workflows, which was later utilised by implementation designers

Senior Customer Service Agent Kaseya (Permanent) // Oct 2010 - Nov 2011

Technical Support (Level 2) Visionstream // Dec 2009 - Sep 2010

Technical Analyst Gen-i, NZ // Oct 2007 - May 2009

Volunteering and Travel in Asia Pacific // August 2005 - August 2007

Volunteered as a house builder in Thailand for a year following the 2004 tsunami, enabling locals to build 106 houses. Taught myself basic spoken & written Thai to aid communications between local and volunteers.

# **Technical Support (Level 3)**

IBM Warwick, UK (Permanent) // Sep 2003 - Jun 2005

Worked shifts providing 24x7 support in a Windows/AIX/Solaris server farm.

#### Application Developer (Java)

IBM Portsmouth, UK // Sep 2001 - Sep 2003

Sole developer, responsible for the full lifecycle design, development and deployment of a website to register staff for a biennial conference, built using Java, JSPs & JDBC. Mentored a junior dev to customise the site for another conference.

### **INTERESTS**

Health tech products that improve people's wellbeing via psychology

The design & architecture of almost everything from housing to software

Sci-fi TV shows

Avid traveller, visited 10 countries in 12 years in-between various IT contracts while living in NZ